# ARIELL N. SCOTT

www.linkedin.com/in/ariell-scott-bb3b2893 | (860) 930-2275 | scott.ariell00@gmail.com | github.com/as98250

# **Professional Summary**

Accomplished young professional with over 6 years of customer service experience. Over the past 2 years, I have developed the skills and applied the training I received while obtaining a Bachelors of Science in Business Administration at The University of North Carolina at Charlotte. As a Customer Relationship Specials with The Hartford, I have polished my leadership, communication, and organizational skills. I will utilize these skills as a valuable asset & contributor, as I continue my career progression.

### Skills

- Excellent Verbal & Written Communication
- Proactive & Responsive Customer Service
- Enforce and monitor SOP
- System Integration
- Research and Analytics
- Operations Management
- Algorithm in Calculating Variances

- Development of SOP (standard operating procedure)
- Training and Leadership
- Building client Relationships
- Payroll and Accounts Receivable
- Database Reporting
- Quality Assurance
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- API's: Web, Third Party, Server Side

# Work History

3<sup>rd</sup> Party Data Associate- Data Specialist

05/2020 to Present

The Hartford - Charlotte, NC

- Support 3PD Lead(s) in development and maintenance of team/Lines of Business/Segment roadmaps, contract research
   & tracking
- Manage team mailbox and 3PD Hub inventory, content and access management to ensure governance.
- Creation and updating of team documents, trackers or presentation material.
- Support Enterprise reporting needs including spend and various program metrics.
  - Enterprise is the "Umbrella" in terms of the numerous departments within The Hartford. These departments do not
    communicate, Enterprise is the department that bridges the communication gap, capitalizing on contracts and
    funding.
- Partners with procurement NDAs, contract funding and low complex renewals
- Support monitoring of SLA's, budget/supplier invoice management, usage management, metric reporting, document creation, etc.
- Conduct vendor screenings/market scans of external data sources and providers

#### **Customer Relationship Specialist III**

02/2020 to Present

The Hartford - Charlotte, NC

#### Advanced Skill Trained-

o Process specialty transactions that cannot be processed by standard trained representatives. Scope of rewrite transactions –

- Adding Property or Liability to a policy that does not currently have the coverage, changing the
  predominant state, changing the predominant company code, change in Underwriting Companies, and
  change in program type.
- o Requires extreme attention to detail, great organization skills, and ability to work with multiple Java Sessions at once to rewrite the policy in the SQL system. Must have the ability to read and decipher rating pages which are in the form of algorithms.

#### Stag One Rep

o StagOne agents are valued agents who write a large number of policies with us. StagOne reps are specially trained reps who can handle these clients large scale request and some of the more complicated transactions. Our roll as StagOne reps is to continue to build the relationship with those clients in order to get the agents to write more business with the company.

#### Handle escalations

o Managers have little free time in the day to get to all escalated calls or unhappy clients. My role is to take the escalation calls in place of management. I collect all the information on the account, get an understanding of the issue at hand, find a suitable solution and send a write up of the incident to my manager.

#### **Customer Relationship Specialist II**

01/2019 to 02/2020

The Hartford - Charlotte, NC

- Balance capacity of phone and paper transactions based on the daily demand, utilizing multiple monitors, systems, and
  working across departments while maintaining top level metric requirements.
  - o Department Goal: 5 Calls per Hour; 3 Transactions per Hour; 10 min Handle time; 91% Schedule Adherence.
  - o My 2019 Average: 6.35 Calls per Hour; 4.51; 8.09 min Handle time; 93.3% Schedule Adherence.
- Mentor Play a direct role in the training and developing of new hires' skills and product knowledge to prepare them to be an essential asset to the company.
- Monitor and coach new talent by conducting side by side call listening, training excises, and process confirmation on completed work.
- Help trainees identify and polish their strengths and set SMART (Specific, Measurable, Achievable, Realistic, Timely) Goals
  to overcome weaknesses.
- Research and rework account interactions that have been escalated to management. Working with the client to rebuild the relationship and correct the error at hand, sending a closing summary to management.
- Contribute to the development and restructuring of SOP.

#### Customer Relationship Specialist I

02/2018 to 01/2019

The Hartford - Charlotte, NC

- Developed product knowledge of Small Commercial Business offerings.
- Became familiar with Hartford Underwriting guidelines to streamline and filter through risks that can be handled by non-licensed reps, while remaining in compliance.
- Worked with agents and small business owners to create strong relationships and educate them on product offerings.
- Provided formal quotes on coverage's and document all outgoing correspondence per Hartford guidelines.
- Analyzed billing accounts and polices to uncover discrepancies, overlapping coverage and find gaps in coverage.

#### Administrative Assistant and Marketing Coordinator

07/2017 to 02/2018

#### Carolina United Realty

• Oversee all tenant accounts, monitoring accounts receivable and making sure accounts maintain in good standing.

- Contact late tenants throughout the week and update pending eviction lists. Documenting non-responsive tenants and scheduling follow-ups.
- New client acquisition and work as the liaison for all applicants.
- Schedule and host open houses and private showings for available rental properties.
- Review applicant background checks to determine if the applicant should be presented to the homeowner. Essentially, weighing the risk of the applicant, within North Carolina Fair Housing Laws.
- Marketing Coordinator- Responsible for all company marketing content. This included promoting our properties and brand, making sure all of our property listings are current on our company sites and syndicated housing host sites.
- Conduct pre-move in walk through inspection to catalog and document the condition of the home.
- Schedule and follow up on new tenants to insure customer satisfaction.

### Technical Skills

- Advanced Knowledge of Word, Excel and PowerPoint
- Proficient in SQL and Tableau
- Familiar with ERP systems
- Java Oracle SQL
- SAP
- 65 WPM

### Education

The University of North Carolina at Charlotte – 2017

**Bachelor of Science** in Business Administration with a Marketing focus.

The Coding Bootcamp at The University of North Carolina at Charlotte – 2021 (currently enrolled)

# Sample Work

**Drink and Eatery App:** My team was tasked with creating an application using two 3rd Party APIs. We created an application that returned cocktail and food recipes based on increaties and cuisine type. This project utilizes: HTML, CSS, Pure CSS Framework, JavaScript, and Third Party API's **Drink and Eatery App** 

**Professional Portfolio:** My professional portfolio is a true representation of my growth as I move through the coding bootcamp. This portfolio utilizes: HTML, CSS, CSS Framework, and JavaScript. <u>Ariell Scott Portfolio</u>

JavaScript Coding Quiz: The goal of this assignment was to exercise my knowledge of JavaScript. Code It Or Not Quiz

# Awards/ Recognition

Bill Bloom Award- 2020- Executive VP recognized the top Customer Service Performers

Service Star 2018-2020- Quarterly recognition for the top performers.